很久以前
在一个遥远的星系里…
《星球大战》
《前传：克隆人的进攻》
银河参议院
正处乱世之秋
数以千计的恒星系已声明意图脱离共和
这一分裂运动
在神秘的杜库伯爵领导下
令已经为数不多的绝地武士
在维护银河系和平与秩序时困难重重
前任纳布皇后
阿米达拉参议员
正返回银河参议院
就建立共和军队
以协助处于弱势的绝地武士
这一重要议题进行投票…
参议员，我们正准备在克拉斯肯（共和国首都）着陆
Senator, we're making our final approach into Coruscant.
很好，中尉
Very good, Lieutenant.
平安到达
We made it.
可能是我错了
I guess I was wrong.
根本没有危险
There was no danger at all.
克黛尔
Cordé.
夫人，真对不起
Milady, I'm so sorry.
我有辱你的使命，参议员
I've failed you, Senator.
不
No.
夫人，这里还是很危险
Milady, you're still in danger here.
- 我真不该回来 - 但这次投票至关重要
- I shouldn't have come back. - This vote is very important.
你尽了你的职责，克黛尔也是，我们走吧
You did your duty. Cordé did hers. Now, come.
阿米达拉参议员，请走吧
Senator Amidala, please.
朋友们，我不知道还能拖延多久再投票
I don't know how much longer I can hold off the vote, my friends.
越来越多的星系正在投靠分裂派
More and more star systems are joining the separatists.
如果他们真的和我们一分为二…
If they do break away…
我决不允许维系了千年之久的共和国…
I will not let this Republic that has stood for a thousand years…
分崩离析
be split in two.
谈判不会失败的
My negotiations will not fail.
要是他们真的和我们决裂了…
If they do, you must realize…
你得知道现有的绝地武士远不足以保护共和国
there aren't enough Jedi to protect the Republic.
我们只是和平守护者，而不是战士
We're keepers of the peace, not soldiers.
尤达大师
Master Yoda…
你认为战争真会爆发吗？
do you think it will really come to war?
唔，黑暗势力笼罩了一切
The dark side clouds everything.
不可能预见未来会如何
Impossible to see the future is.
[胡图族语]反分裂委员会已经抵达，阁下
The Loyalist Committee has arrived, Your Honor.
- 很好 - [胡图族语] 等候您的指示
- Good. - [Hutu language]
请他们进来
Send them in.
这事我们以后再议
We will discuss this matter later.
阿米达拉参议员，在着陆区发生的不幸…
Senator Amidala, your tragedy on the landing platform…
太可怕了
terrible.
看到你安然无恙，让我甚感欣慰
Seeing you alive brings warm feelings to my heart.
你知道谁是幕后主使吗？
Do you have any idea who was behind this attack?
有情报表明是纳布卫星上心怀不满的香料采集工干的
Our intelligence points to disgruntled spice miners on the moons of Naboo.
我认为杜克伯爵是幕后主使
I think that Count Dooku was behind it.
他是个政治理想主义者，而不是杀人狂
He is a political idealist, not a murderer.
你知道，夫人，杜克伯爵曾经是个绝地武士
You know, milady, Count Dooku was once a Jedi.
他不会用暗杀这招的，这不符合他的性格
He couldn't assassinate anyone. It's not in his character.
但有一点是肯定的，参议员…
But for certain, Senator…
你的处境极为危险
in grave danger you are.
绝地大师，我能提议…
MasterJedi, may I suggest…
将参议员置于你仁慈的保护之下吗？
the senator be placed under the protection of your graces?
在这样的紧张局势下，你以为这真的是明智之举吗？
Do you really think that's a wise decision under these stressful times?
首相，请容我冒昧进言，我认为
Chancellor, if I may comment, I do not believe…
形势并没那么严重…？
The situation is that serious?
不，我不这么认为，参议员
No, but I do, Senator.
我完全明白，加强戒备
I realize all too well that additional security…
可能会给你带来不便
might be disruptive for you…
但如果是你的熟人
but perhaps someone you're familiar with.
一个老朋友，比如欧比旺·肯诺比大师…
An old friend, like Master Kenobi.
这完全有可能
That's possible.
他刚解决完安尼森的边界争端回来
He's just returned from a border dispute on Ansion.
答应我，夫人，行吗？
Do it for me, milady. Please?
想到有可能会失去你
The thought of losing you…
真令人难以接受
is unbearable.
我会让欧比旺立刻向你报到，夫人
I will have Obi-Wan report to you immediately, milady.
谢谢你，温杜大师
Thank you, Master Windu.
- 你好像有点紧张 - 没有的事
- You seem a little on edge. - Not at all.
我还没见你这么紧张过
I haven't felt you this tense
自从上次我们身陷暗之巢穴以来
since we fell into that nest of gundarks.
是你掉进那个可怕的地方，师父
You fell into that nightmare, Master…
而我救了你，记得吗？
and I rescued you, remember?
哦…对喔…
Oh… yes.
你都出汗了，放轻松，深呼吸
You're sweating. Relax. Take a deep breath.
我有十年没见她了，师父
I haven't seen her in ten years, Master.
欧比？欧比！
Obi? Obi!
大师，见到你真开心！
Mesa so smilen to seein yousa!
很高兴再见到你，加加
Good to see you again, JarJar.
参议员，帕德梅
Senator Padmé.
大师请过来！瞧，瞧，参议员
Mesa palos here! Lookie, lookie, Senator.
绝地武士们来了
Desa Jedi arriven.
很荣幸再见到你，夫人
It's a great pleasure to see you again, milady.
真是好久不见了，肯诺比大师
It has been far too long, Master Kenobi.
安？
Ani?
- 天哪，你长大了 - 你也一样
- My goodness, you've grown. - So have you.
我是说，变得更漂亮了
Grown more beautiful, I mean.
哦，我…我是说，以一个参议员的标准来说
Well, for a senator, I mean.
安，你还是你那个我在塔图因星认识的小男孩一样
Ani, you'll always be that little boy I knew on Tatooine.
夫人，我们保证不会干扰你的行动的
Our presence here will be invisible, milady, I can assure you.
我是泰弗上尉，负责女皇陛下的保安
I'm Captain Typho of Her Majesty's security service.
吉米拉女皇已经得知你们的使命
Queen Jamillia has been informed of your assignment.
很感谢你能来，肯诺比大师
I am grateful you are here, Master Kenobi.
目前形势比参议员所想的要危险得多
The situation is more dangerous than the senator will admit.
我想要的不是安全防卫，而是答案
I don't need more security. I need answers.
我想知道是谁想杀我
I want to know who's trying to kill me.
我们是来保护你的，参议员，不是来做调查的
We are here to protect you, Senator, not to start an investigation.
我们会查到是谁干的，帕德梅
We will find out who's trying to kill you, Padmé.
我向你保证
I promise you.
我们不会去做职责之外的事，我年轻的徒弟
We will not exceed our mandate, my young Padawan learner.
我认为这是为了更好地保护她，师父
I meant that in the interest of protecting her, Master, of course.
不要再多费口舌了，安纳金
We will not go through this exercise again, Anakin…
你要服从我的指挥
and you will pay attention to my lead.
- 为什么？ - 什么？
- Why? - What?
如果不去查谁是凶手，我们还为什么被派到她这儿来呢？
Why else do you think we were assigned to her if not to find the killer?
保护她是保安的差事，不是绝地武士的职责
Protection is a job for local security, not Jedi.
伤及无辜了，大师，我们的任务包含了追查凶手
It's overkill, Master. Investigation is implied in our mandate.
我们要严格执行参议会的指令
We will do exactly as the council has instructed.
你会知道你是来干么的，小伙子
And you will learn your place, young one.
也许只要你们来了
Perhaps with merely your presence…
这次恐吓行动就会疑云尽释
the mystery surrounding this threat will be revealed.
现在，如能蒙你们谅解
Now, if you'll excuse me…
我要告退了
I will retire.
你们来了我感觉好多了
I know I'll feel better having you here.
每层楼我都会安排警卫站岗…
I'll have an officer stationed on every floor…
我自己在楼下的控制中心
and I'll be in the control center downstairs.
安，又见到你真开兴
Mesa busten wit happiness seein yousa again, Ani.
她都快认不出我了，加加
She hardly even recognized me, JarJar.
离开她之后我天天都想着她
I've thought about her every day since we parted and…
可她把我全忘了
she's forgotten me completely.
她很开心
Shesa happy.
偶好久没看她这么开心过啦
Happier den mesa seein her in a longo time.
安纳金，你太看重负面的东西了，你得留心你的意念
You're focusing on the negative, Anakin. Be mindful of your thoughts.
她见到我们很高兴
She was pleased to see us.
我们现在去检查一下保安吧
Now, let's check the security.
我击中了飞船，但他们用了替身
I hit the ship, but they used a decoy.
这次我们得用更妙的手段，扎姆
We'll have to try something more subtle this time, Zam.
我的委托人有点等得不耐烦了
My client is getting impatient.
拿着这个，当心，这玩艺儿是剧毒的
Take these. Be careful. They're very poisonous.
扎姆，这次可别出什么错
And, Zam, there can be no mistakes this time.
泰弗上尉在楼下安排了重兵把守
Captain Typho has more than enough men downstairs.
刺客绝对不会走这条路的
No assassin would try that way.
- 这儿有什么情况吗？ - 毫无动静
- Any activity up here? - Quiet as a tomb.
我不喜欢就这样等着她出事
I don't like just waiting here for something to happen to her.
- 什么事？ - 她遮住了镜头
- What's going on? - She covered the cameras.
我想她肯定不喜欢我这么监视她
I don't think she liked me watching her.
她怎么想的？
What is she thinking?
她给R2下指令，一旦有入侵者就来通知我们
She programmed R2 to warn us if there is an intruder.
要杀一个参议员的方法很多
There are many other ways to kill a senator.
我知道，但我们不是要抓住这个刺客吗，师父？
I know, but we also want to catch this assassin, don't we, Master?
你在用她做诱饵
You're using her as bait.
这是她的主意
It was her idea.
放心，她不会出事的
Don't worry. No harm will come to her.
我能感应到那间房里发生的一切
I can sense everything going on in that room.
相信我
Trust me.
这太冒险了
It's too risky.
另外，你的感应也没那么灵敏，我的年轻徒弟
Besides, your senses aren't that attuned, my young apprentice.
你的就很灵吗？
And yours are?
也许吧
Possibly.
你看起来很疲倦
You look tired.
我一直睡不好觉
I don't sleep well anymore.
因为你母亲？
Because of your mother?
不知道为什么我老梦到她
I don't know why I keep dreaming about her.
过段时间就会好的
Dreams pass in time.
我宁愿梦到帕德梅
I'd much rather dream about Padmé.
重回她的身边已经…令人陶醉了
Just being around her again is… intoxicating.
留心你的意念，安纳金，他们会背叛你
Be mindful of your thoughts, Anakin. They betray you.
你已经宣誓服从绝地法规…
You've made a commitment to theJedi order…
宣誓是不能轻易反悔的
a commitment not easily broken.
还要记住，她是个政客，政客是不能相信的
And don't forget, she's a politician. They're not to be trusted.
她和参议会里的其它人不一样，师父
She's not like the others in the senate, Master.
我的经验是
It is my experience that senators focus…
议员们只会取悦能资助他们选举的人
only on pleasing those who fund their campaigns…
并且可以完全无视民主的真义…
and they're in no means scared of forgetting the niceties of democracy…
- 就为了得到赞助 - 别对我说教啦
- in order to get those funds. - Not another lecture.
至少别再提什么政客筹钱的事
At least not on the economics of politics.
还有，你是一概而论
And besides, you're generalizing.
首相看起来没就那么腐败
The chancellor doesn't appear to be corrupt.
帕裴丁是个老政客
Palpatine is a politician.
我发现他很善于
I have observed that he is very clever…
处理和迎合议员们的怒气和偏见
in following the passions and the prejudices of the senators.
我觉得他是个好人
I think he's a good man…
我也感觉应到了
I sense it too.
待这儿别动！
Stay here!
你没事吧，夫人？
Are you all right, milady?
妈的怎么…
What the…
[胡图族语]
该死的绝地武士！
Jedi poo doo!
- 怎么这么慢？ - 哦，师父，你知道
- What took you so long? - Oh, you know, Master.
- 我一时找不到我要的车… - 他在那儿
- I couldn't find a speeder I liked… - There he is.
有敞篷座舱和足够速度的那种
With the open cockpit and the right speed capabilities.
如果你肯多花功夫练剑而不是耍小聪明的话…
If you spent as long practicing your saber techniques as you do your wit…
你的剑术就足以和尤达大师抗衡了
you would rival Master Yoda as a swordsman.
我想我已经做到了
I thought I already did.
你想得美，我年轻的徒弟
Only in your mind, my very young apprentice.
拉高，安纳金，快拉高！
Pull up, Anakin. Pull up!
你知道我不喜欢你这么做
You know I don't like it when you do that.
抱歉，师父 我忘了你不喜欢飞行
Sorry, Master. I forgot you don't like flying.
我不是不喜欢，但你这么做和自杀没什么两样！
I don't mind flying, but what you're doing is suicide!
安纳金！我跟你说了多少次了…
Anakin! How many times have I told you…
离电源耦合器远点！
stay away from power couplings!
真爽！
That was good!
你去哪儿？他往那边去了
Where are you going? He went that way.
大师，如果我们再追下去的话
Master, if we keep this chase going any longer…
那家伙会被逼急的…
that creep is gonna end up deep-fried…
而且，我个人更想知道
and, personally, I'd like to find out
他是谁？受谁指使？
who he is and who he's working for.
这是条捷径，我想
This is a shortcut… I think.
好啦，你把他跟丢了
Well, you've lost him.
我非常抱歉，大师
I'm deeply sorry, Master.
这是条捷径，安纳金
That was some shortcut, Anakin.
他走的完全是另一条路
He went completely the other way.
- 你再次证明了… - 对不起我失陪一会儿
- Once again you've proved… - If you'll excuse me.
我最讨厌他这样了
I hate it when he does that.
安纳金！
Anakin!
- 她进夜总会了，大师 - 耐心点
- She went into the club, Master. - Patience.
- 运用你的原力，思考 - 对不起，师父
- Use the Force. Think. - Sorry, Master.
- 他进去是想躲起来，不是要逃走 - 是的，师父
- He went in there to hide, not to run. - Yes, Master.
- 下次可别弄丢了 - 是，师父
- Next time, try not to lose it. - Yes, Master.
- 武器就是你的生命 - 我会尽力的，师父
- This weapon is your life. - I try, Master.
为什么我觉得总有一天我会死在你手上？
Why do I get the feeling you're going to be the death of me?
千万别这么说，师父
Don't say that, Master.
你对我就像父亲一样
You're the closest thing I have to a father.
那你为什么不听我的话？
Then why don't you listen to me?
我正在努力
I am trying.
你能看到他吗？
Can you see him?
我想“他”是个女的…
I think he is a she…
而且她还会伪装
and I think she is a changeling.
这样的话，你得加倍小心了
In that case, be extra careful.
- 你去找她吧 - 你去哪儿，师父？
- Go and find her. - Where are you going, Master?
弄杯喝的
For a drink.
谢谢
Thank you.
你想买死亡之杖吗？
You wanna buy some death sticks?
你不想向我兜售死亡之杖
You don't want to sell me death sticks.
我不想向你兜售死亡之杖
I don't want to sell you death sticks.
你想回家反省你的一生
You want to go home and rethink your life.
我想回家反省我的一生
I want to go home and rethink my life.
别害怕
Easy.
绝地武士执行公务，回去继续喝酒吧
Jedi business. Go back to your drinks.
知道你要杀的是谁吗？
Do you know who it was you were trying to kill?
是从纳布来的一个参议员
It was a senator from Naboo.
- 谁是你的雇主？ - 只是工作而已
- And who hired you? - It was just a job.
雇主是谁？告诉我们
Who hired you? Tell us.
快告诉我们！
Tell us now!
是个赏金猎人，名叫…
It was a bounty hunter called…
[外星语]Wee shahnit… sleemo.
毒镖
Toxic dart.
你必须追查这个赏金猎人，欧比旺
Track down this bounty hunter you must, Obi-Wan.
更重要的是，查出他的主子是谁
Most importantly, find out who he's working for.
阿米达拉参议员怎么办？
What about Senator Amidala?
她仍然需要保护
She will still need protecting.
你的徒弟，交给他办
Handle that your Padawan will.
安纳金，你护送参议员回她的纳布母星
Anakin, escort the senator back to her home planet of Naboo.
她在那儿会很安全，不要用真名乘坐交通工具
She'll be safer there. And don't use registered transport.
以难民的身份上路
Travel as refugees.
身为反对派的领导，参议员不会…
As the leader of the opposition, it will be very difficult…
…轻易离开首都的
to get Senator Amidala to leave the capital.
在我们没抓住真凶之前
Until caught this killer is…
她必须尊重我们的决定
our judgment she must respect.
安纳金，你去参议院…
Anakin, go to the senate…
请帕裴丁首相和她谈谈这事
and ask Chancellor Palpatine to speak with her about this matter.
我会和她谈的
I will talk with her.
阿米达拉参议员是不会拒绝行政命令的
Senator Amidala will not refuse an executive order.
我很了解她，这你可以放心
I know her well enough to assure you of that.
多谢阁下
Thank you, Your Excellency.
这么说，他们终于给了你一个任务
And so, they've finally given you an assignment.
你的耐心得到回报了
Your patience has paid off.
是你的教导有功，并非我的耐心
Your guidance more than my patience.
你无须指导，安纳金
You don't need guidance, Anakin.
慢慢的，你要学会相信自己的感觉
In time, you will learn to trust your feelings.
那时候你就会战无不胜了
Then you will be invincible.
我说过很多次了：
I have said it many times:
你是我所见过的绝地武士里天分最高的
You are the most gifted Jedi I have ever met.
多谢阁下
Thank you, Your Excellency.
我要看你成为最伟大的绝地武士，安纳金
I see you becoming the greatest of all theJedi, Anakin…
甚至比尤达大师更强
even more powerful than Master Yoda.
我为我徒弟担心
I am concerned for my Padawan.
他还不具备独立执行这项任务的能力
He is not ready to be given this assignment on his own yet.
参议会对这个决定是有信心的，欧比旺
The council is confident in its decision, Obi-Wan.
这孩子有身具异能
The boy has exceptional skills.
但他还有很多要学，大师
But he still has much to learn, Master.
他的能力令他，唔，自以为是
His abilities have made him, well, arrogant.
不错，不错
Yes.
这快成了绝地武士的通病了
A flaw more and more common among Jedi.
过分自信了，他们
Too sure of themselves they are.
连年长些的，更有经验的也是这样
Even the older, more experienced ones.
记住，欧比旺，如果预言真的应验…
Remember, Obi-Wan, if the prophecy is true…
你徒弟是唯一一个
your apprentice is the only one
能让原力恢复平衡的人
who can bring the Force back into balance.
我将缺席一段时日
I'm taking an extended leave of absence.
请你代我负起议会的职责
It will be your responsibility to take my place in the senate.
代理人宾克斯，我信得过你
Representative Binks, I know I can count on you.
很荣幸我能肩服如此重担
Mesa honored to be taking on dissa heavy burden.
我恭受此命，但是，嗯…
Mesa accept this with muy, muy humility and…
加加，我不想给你带来麻烦
JarJar, I don't wish to hold you up.
我知道你有很多事要做
I'm sure you have a great deal to do.
当然
Of course.
夫人
Milady.
我也不喜欢躲躲藏藏的
I do not like this idea of hiding.
别担心
Don't worry.
既然参议会已经发令调查
Now that the council has ordered an investigation…
欧比旺大师很快就会找到那个赏金猎人的
it won't take Master Obi-Wan long to find this bounty hunter.
我花了一年从事抵制建军法案的工作
I haven't worked for a year to defeat the Military Creation Act…
却不能在此决定它的命运
to not be here when its fate is decided.
有时候我们不得不放弃尊严…
Sometimes we must let go of our pride…
做我们不得不做的事
and do what is requested of us.
安纳金，你长大了
Anakin, you've grown up.
欧比旺大师不希望看到这点
Master Obi-Wan manages not to see it.
别胡说
Don't get me wrong.
欧比旺是个好师父
Obi-Wan is a great mentor.
与尤达大师一样睿智
As wise as Master Yoda and…
和温杜大师一样有力
as powerful as Master Windu.
我作为他的徒弟很感激他
I am truly thankful to be his apprentice.
在某些方面… 许多方面…
In some ways… a lot of ways…
我其实已经超越了他
I'm really ahead of him.
我已经准备好接受考验…
I'm ready for the trials…
但他认为我难以捉摸
but he feels that I'm too unpredictable.
他不让我继续前进
He won't let me move on.
- 这肯定很令人沮丧 - 实际更糟
- That must be frustrating. - It's worse.
他总是吹毛求疵，不听忠告
He's overly critical. He never listens.
他… 他不能理解我
He doesn't understand.
太不公平了！
It's not fair!
每个师父都能看到
All mentors have a way of seeing
我们不愿意承认的缺点
more of our faults than we would like.
只有这样我们才能成长
It's the only way we grow.
我明白
I know.
安纳金
Anakin…
别想一步登天
don't try to grow up too fast.
但我已经长大了
But I am grown up.
你自己说的
You said it yourself.
请你别这么看我
Please don't look at me like that.
为什么不行？
Why not?
这让我感觉很不自在
It makes me feel uncomfortable.
抱歉，夫人
Sorry, milady.
- 祝你平安，夫人 - 谢谢你，上尉
- Be safe, milady. - Thank you, Captain.
好好照看多弥，危险现在由你们俩承担了
Take good care of Dormé. The threat's on you two now.
他和我在一起很安全
He'll be safe with me.
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
夫人，不是我的问题 我更担心你
It's not me, milady. I worry about you.
万一他们知道你离开了首都怎么办？
What if they realize you've left the capital?
哦，那么我的绝地守护者就不得不证明他有多厉害了
Well, then myJedi protector will have to prove how good he is.
安纳金
Anakin…
在没和我本人或议会商议之前千万别轻举妄动
don't do anything without first consulting either myself or the council.
是，大师
Yes, Master.
夫人，我会尽快查出阴谋真相的
I'll get to the bottom of this plot quickly, milady.
你很快就可以回来了
You'll be back here in no time.
如能尽快办妥，我感激不尽，绝地大师
I'll be most grateful for your speed, MasterJedi.
- 该动身了 - 我知道
- It's time to go. - I know.
安纳金，愿原力与你同在
Anakin, may the Force be with you.
愿原力与你同在，大师
May the Force be with you, Master.
我突然有点害怕
Suddenly I'm afraid.
这是我头一次独立执行使命，我也有点害怕
This is my first assignment on my own. I am too.
别担心，有R2陪着我们呢
Don't worry. We have R2 with us.
我真希望他别干蠢事
I do hope he doesn't try anything foolish.
我更担心她会干蠢事，而不是他
I'd be more concerned about her doing something than him.
有人要见你，亲爱的！
Someone to see ya, honey!
是个绝地武士，看起来像
Jedi, by the looks of him.
欧比旺！
Obi-Wan!
你好，德克斯
Hello, Dex.
请坐，我一会就来
Take a seat. I'll be right with ya.
- 来杯乔瓦果汁好吗？ - 哦，好的，谢谢
- You wanna cup o'jawa juice? - Oh, yes. Thank you.
老伙计！
Old buddy!
我的朋友，我有什么可以效劳的？
So, my friend, what can I do for ya?
能告诉我这是什么吗？
You can tell me what this is.
哦，你知道吗！
Well, whattaya know!
自我上次在撒泊特瑞太空外沿探矿以来
I ain't seen one of these since I was prospectin'…
我是头一次见到这玩艺儿
on Subterrel, beyond the outer rim.
能告诉我它从哪儿来的吗？多谢
Can you tell me where it came from?
这是克隆人的玩艺儿
This baby belongs to them cloners.
你拿来的是一只卡米罗飞镖
What you got here is a Kamino saberdart.
奇怪分析部门怎么没发现呢？
I wonder why it didn't show up in the analysis archives.
是这些刀锋上有趣的小切口告诉我的
It's these funny little cuts on the side that give it away.
那些分析机器人只会分析符号，嘿！
Those analysis droids only focus on symbols.
我原以为你们绝地武士会更清楚…
I should think that you Jedi would have more respect…
知识和智慧之间的区别呢
for the difference between knowledge and…wisdom.
嗯，要是机器人也能思考…
Well, if droids could think…
我们就没有立足之地了，不是吗？
there'd be none of us here, would there?
卡米罗，我从来没听说过它在共和国之内吗？
Kamino. I'm not familiar with it. Is it in the Republic?
不，不 他在太空外沿
No, no. It's beyond the outer rim.
我想是在瑞斯惑星之外大约12秒距（1秒＝3.26光年）的地方
I'd say about 12 parsecs outside the Rishi Maze.
很容易找，连你们部门里的机器人都找得到
Should be easy to find, even for those droids in your archives.
这些卡米罗人与世隔绝
These Kaminoans keep to themselves.
他们都是克隆人，很完美的那种
They're cloners. Damn good ones too.
- 克隆人？他们友好吗？ - 那就看情况了
- Cloners. Are they friendly? - Depends.
怎么说，德克斯？
Depends on what, Dex?
要看你的态度如何…
On how good your manners are…
还有你的… 钱包有多鼓
and how big your… pocketbook is.
- 你要帮忙吗？ - 是的，是的
- Did you call for assistance? - Yes, I did.
有什么问题，肯诺比大师？
Are you having a problem, Master Kenobi?
是的，嗯，我要找一个叫卡米罗的星系
Yes, I'm looking for a planetary system called Kamino.
- 卡米罗 - 在档案星图里找不到的
- Kamino. - It doesn't show up on the archive charts.
卡米罗，这不是我熟悉的星系
Kamino. It's not a system I'm familiar with.
你确定坐标没搞错吗？
Are you sure you have the right coordinates?
根据我的情报，它应该位于这个像限
According to my information, it should appear in this quadrant here…
在瑞斯惑星的南面
just south of the Rishi Maze.
我不得不告诉你，好像你找的星系
I hate to say it, but it looks like the system you're searching for…
根本不存在
doesn't exist.
不可能，也许是档案不全
Impossible. Perhaps the archives are incomplete.
我们资料里没有的东西
If an item does not appear in our records…
就是不存在的
it does not exist.
嘿！！机器人不许进来！
Hey, you! No droids!
走开！
Get outta here!
谢谢你，R2
Thank you, R2.
这一定很困难，作为一个绝地武士终生立誓…
Must be difficult, having sworn your life to the Jedi…
不能去你喜欢的地方，做你喜欢的事
not being able to visit the places you like or do the things you like.
还不能和你喜欢的人在一起
Or be with the people that I love.
你能恋爱吗？
Are you allowed to love?
我想绝地武士是禁止恋爱的
I thought that was forbidden for a Jedi.
配偶，不许有
Attachment is forbidden.
财产，不许有
Possession is forbidden.
怜悯，我把它定义为无条件的爱
Compassion, which I would define as unconditional love…
就是一个绝地武士生活的中心
is central to a Jedi's life.
因此你也可以说我们是被鼓励去爱的
So you might say that we are encouraged to love.
你的变化真大
You've changed so much.
你的变化真小
You haven't changed a bit.
你和我梦中所见一般无二
You're exactly the way I remember you in my dreams.
伸出手来，感应在你们周围的原力
Reach out. Sense the Force around you.
你们必须运用你们的感觉
Use your feelings you must.
孩子们，孩子们！
Younglings. Younglings!
我们来客人了
A visitor we have.
你好，欧比旺大师
Hello, Master Obi-Wan.
你们好
Hello.
很抱歉打扰了，大师
I'm sorry to disturb you, Master.
我能帮上什么忙吗，欧比旺？嗯？
What help can I be, Obi-Wan?
我在找一位老友向我描述的星球
I'm looking for a planet described to me by an old friend.
我相信他，但这个星系在我们的档案星图里没有
I trust him, but the systems don't show on the archive maps.
一颗星球，欧比旺大师找不到了
Lost a planet Master Obi-Wan has.
真难为情！
How embarrassing!
利安，把帘子拉上
Liam, the shades.
都到星图阅读器这儿来
Gather round the map reader.
澄心静虑
Clear your minds…
我们就会找到欧比旺的不听话的星球
and find Obi-Wan's wayward planet we will.
它应该在…这儿…
It ought to be here…
可这儿什么也没有
but it isn't.
重力将这一区域所有星球拉向这一点
Gravity is pulling all the stars in the area towards this spot.
重力的影像还在…
Gravity's silhouette remains…
但这颗星和它所有行星的影像…
but the star and all the planets…
都不见了
disappeared they have.
怎么会这样的？
How can this be?
有人知道吗？
A thought?
谁知道？
Anyone.
大师？
Master?
是有人把它从档案内存里清除掉了
Because someone erased it from the archive memory.
真是太棒了，孩子的思想
Truly wonderful the mind of a child is.
这孩子说的没错
The Padawan is right.
去引力中心
Go to the center of gravity's pull…
你会找到你的星球，
and find your planet you will.
数据肯定被清除了
The data must have been erased.
但是，谁能在档案中清除资料呢？
But who could empty information from the archives?
这是不可能的吗？
Isn't that impossible?
这是个危险而恼人的谜，
Dangerous and disturbing this puzzle is.
只有绝地武士才能清除文件
Only a Jedi could have erased those files.
但谁干的？为什么？很难回答
But who and why, harder to answer.
我会深思这个问题的，
Meditate on this I will.
我曾是有史以来最年轻的女皇
I wasn't the youngest queen ever elected…
但现在回想起来
but now that I think back on it,
我不知道自己的年龄是否足够
I'm not sure I was old enough.
我不知道我是否准备好了
I'm not sure I was ready.
你为之服务的人民觉得你是称职的
The people you served thought you did a good job.
我听说他们甚至想修改宪法…
I heard they even tried to amend the constitution…
让你继续留任
so you could stay in office.
两届任期满后我真是松了一口气
I was relieved when my two terms were up.
但女皇陛下让我担任参议员的时候
But when the queen asked me to serve as senator…
我又难以拒绝她
I couldn't refuse her.
我赞同女皇的决定，我认为共和国很需要你
I agree with her. I think the Republic needs you.
很高兴你选择了继续服务大众
I'm glad that you chose to serve.
如果参议院投票建军
If the senate votes to create an army,
这肯定会让我们陷于内战
it's sure to push us into a civil war.
不可思议！
It's unthinkable!
从未发生过大规模的战争
There hasn't been a full-scale war
自共和国成立以来
since the formation of the Republic.
你认为有可能通过谈判
Do you see any way through negotiations…
让分裂派重回共和吗？
to bring the separatists back into the Republic?
如果他们有危机感，这是不可能的
Not if they feel threatened.
我想他们会求助于贸易同盟或商业协会
They'll turn to the Trade Federations or the Commerce Guilds for help.
出乎意料的是…
It's outrageous…
经过最高法院四轮审讯…
but after four trials in the Supreme Court…
纽特·刚瑞仍然是贸易同盟总督
Nute Gunray is still the viceroy of the Trade Federation.
我怕参议会无力解决这一危机
I fear the senate is powerless to resolve this crisis.
我们必须对共和国有信心
We must keep our faith in the Republic.
一旦不相信民主，我们就失去了民主
The day we stop believing democracy can work is the day we lose it.
让我们祈祷永远不会有那么一天吧
Let's pray that day never comes.
同时，你还得考虑自身的安全
In the meantime, we must consider your own safety.
你有什么建议，绝地大师？
What is your suggestion, Master Jedi?
安纳金还不是绝地武士 他还只是个学徒
Anakin's not a Jedi yet. He's still a Padawan learner.
- 但我想… - 等一下
- But I was thinking… - Hold on a minute.
对不起
Excuse me.
我在想也许我能在这个湖泊区待下来
I was thinking I would stay in the lake country.
那儿有些地方人迹罕至
There are some places up there that are very isolated.
对不起，在这儿我负责你的安全，夫人
Excuse me. I'm in charge of security here, milady.
这是我的家乡
And this is my home.
我再熟悉不过了
I know it very well.
所以我们才会到这儿
That is why we're here.
我想明智的做法是…
I think it would be wise…
在这种情况下你听取听我的意见
if you took advantage of my knowledge in this instance.
抱歉，夫人
Sorry, milady.
太好了，那么就这么定了
Perfect. It's settled, then.
就在这儿，R4，在它应该在的地方
There it is, R4, right where it should be.
我们失踪的卡米罗星球
Our missing planet Kamino.
绝地大师
MasterJedi.
首相大人正恭候你的到来
The prime minister is expecting you.
- 首相知道我要来？ - 当然
- I'm expected? - Of course.
他渴望与你会晤
He is anxious to meet you.
过了这么多年
After all these years…
我们都开始想你不会来了
we were beginning to think you weren't coming.
现在，这边请
Now, please, this way.
请允许我向你介绍拉马·苏
May I present Lama Su…
卡米罗星的首相
prime minister of Kamino.
这是绝地大师…
And this is MasterJedi…
欧比旺·肯诺比
Obi-Wan Kenobi.
我相信你在这里会很愉快
I trust you're going to enjoy your stay.
请
Please.
现在言归正传
And now to business.
你听到我们的进度如期完成了一定会很高兴
You will be delighted to hear that we are on schedule.
二十万个单位已整装待发
200, 000 units are ready…
还有一百万正在生产
with a million more well on the way.
好消息
That's good news.
请告诉你们的西佛·迪亚斯大师…
Please tell your Master Sifo-Dyas…
他的订单会如期交货的
that his order will be met on time.
对不起，哪位大师？
I'm sorry. Master…
绝地大师西佛·迪亚斯仍然…
Jedi Master Sifo-Dyas is still…
占据绝地议会的领导地位，是不是？
a leading member of theJedi Council, is he not?
西佛·迪亚斯大师在十年前就死了
Master Sifo-Dyas was killed almost ten years ago.
听到这消息我真难过
I'm so sorry to hear that.
但我确信他会为我们给他建造的军队而骄傲的
But I'm sure he would have been proud of the army we've built for him.
军队？
The army?
是的，一支复制军队，我必须说…
Yes, a clone army, and I must say…
一支我们所建造的最完美的军队
one of the finest we've ever created.
请告诉我，首相大人
Tell me, Prime Minister…
我们的大师什么时候为军队的事和你联系的？
when my master first contacted you about the army…
他…他说了是为谁建造的吗？
did he say who it was for?
当然说了
Of course he did.
这是为共和国建造的军队
This army is for the Republic.
但你一定急于亲自检阅一下
But you must be anxious to inspect the units for yourself.
这就是我来的目的
That's why I'm here.
我们以前一放学就来这儿
We used to come here for school retreat.
我们会每天游到那个小岛
We would swim to that island every day.
我喜欢这湖水
I love the water.
我们会躺在沙滩上让阳光把身体晒乾
We used to lie out on the sand and let the sun dry us…
猜测鸟儿在唱什么歌
and try to guess the names of the birds singing.
我不喜欢沙滩
I don't like sand.
沙子又粗又硬，让人很不舒服
It's coarse and rough and irritating…
而且弄得到处都是
and it gets everywhere.
这儿的沙可不一样
Not like here.
在这里，一切都很柔软
Here, everything is soft…
光滑…
and smooth.
不
No.
我不该这么做的
I shouldn't have done that.
对不起
I'm sorry.
很了不起
Very impressive.
我希望你看了会高兴
I'd hoped you would be pleased.
克隆人能独立思考
Clones can think creatively.
你会发现他们比机器人优越得多
You will find that they are immensely superior to droids.
我们深以我们的战斗训练程序为傲
We take great pride in our combat education and training programs.
这一组是五年前创建的
This group was created about five years ago.
你提到了加速生长
You mentioned growth acceleration.
喔，是的，这很关键
Oh, yes, it's essential.
要不，一个成熟的克隆人就需要一生的时间来生长
Otherwise, a mature clone would take a lifetime to grow.
现在我们用一半的时间就够了
Now we can do it in half the time.
明白了
I see.
他们绝对服从命令
They are totally obedient…
毫无异议地执行任何命令
taking any order without question.
我们改造了他们的遗传结构
We modified their genetic structure…
让他们更为独立于母体
to make them less independent than the original host.
那么谁是母体呢？
And who was the original host?
一个叫强格·费特的赏金猎人
A bounty hunter called Jango Fett.
现在这个赏金猎人在哪儿？
And where is this bounty hunter now?
哦，我们把他留下来了
Oh, we keep him here.
除了要支付他高昂的佣金
Apart from his pay, which is considerable…
费特只有一个要求
Fett demanded only one thing:
他本人的纯复制
An unaltered clone for himself.
- 很奇怪，是吧？ - “纯复制”？
- Curious, isn't it? - "Unaltered"?
纯的基因复制品
Pure genetic replication.
不做任何令之顺服的结构改变
No tampering with the structure to make it more docile…
也不加速生长
and no growth acceleration.
我很想见见这位强格·费特
I should very much like to meet this Jango Fett.
很高兴为你安排会见
I would be very happy to arrange it for you.
很壮观，不是吗？
Magnificent, aren't they?
我不知道
I don't know.
你肯定知道，只是不想告诉我罢了
Sure you do. You just don't want to tell me.
想对我用什么绝地猜心术吗？
You gonna use one of your Jedi mind tricks on me?
那只对意志薄弱的人有效
They only work on the weak-minded.
好了
All right.
我当时12岁 他叫保罗
I was 12. His name was Palo.
我们同在青年立法组织会
We were both in the Legislative Youth Program.
他比我大几岁 很可爱
He was a few years older than I. Very cute.
黑色的卷发，梦一样的眼神
Dark, curly hair. Dreamy eyes.
够了，我可以想像
All right, I get the picture.
他后来怎么了？
Whatever happened to him?
我从政，他则选择了艺术
I went into public service. He went on to become an artist.
也许他更聪明
Maybe he was the smart one.
你不喜欢搞政治的，是吧？
You really don't like politicians, do you?
政客里面我只喜欢两叁个
I like two or three…
但其中一个我一直琢磨不定
but I'm not really sure about one of them.
我认为政治体制没有正常运作
I don't think the system works.
你怎么能让它正常运作？
How would you have it work?
我们需要体制是政治家们…
We need a system where the politicians…
坐在一起并讨论问题…
sit down and discuss the problem…
以全体人民利益为原则达成共识…
agree what's in the best interest of all the people…
然后加以实行
and then do it.
我们正是这么做的
That's exactly what we do.
问题是我们的政策人民不是都能拥护
The trouble is that people don't always agree.
唔，那么就该强制执行
Well, then they should be made to.
- 谁来执行？谁来强制他们？ - 我不知道 总会有人做的
- By whom? Who's gonna make them? - I don't know. Someone.
- 你吗？ - 肯定不是我
- You? - Of course not me.
- 但是某个人 - 某个聪明人
- But someone. - Someone wise.
这在我看来太像专政独裁了
Sounds an awful lot like a dictatorship to me.
唔，只要它有效就行
Well, if it works.
- 你在逗我玩吗？ - 不是
- You're making fun of me. - No.
我怎么敢逗一个参议员玩？
I'd be much too frightened to tease a senator.
安！安，你没事吧？
Ani, are you all right?
伯巴，你父亲在吗？
Boba, is your father here?
在
Yep.
我们能见见他吗？
May we see him?
当然可以
Sure.
爸，唐尔温来了
Dad, Taun We's here.
强格，欢迎你回来
Jango, welcome back.
你的旅行有收获吗？
Was your trip productive?
多少有吧
Fairly.
这位是绝地大师欧比旺 肯诺比
This is Jedi Master Obi-Wan Kenobi.
他是来检查我们进度的
He's come to check on our progress.
你的克隆人相当棒，你一定引以为傲
Your clones are very impressive. You must be very proud.
我只是个普通人，在星际间混口饭吃而已
I'm just a simple man trying to make my way in the universe.
去过星际内部远至克罗斯肯混过饭吃吗？
Ever made your way as far into the interior as Coruscant?
- 去过一两次 - 最近吗？
- Once or twice. - Recently?
也许吧
Possibly.
那你一定认识西佛·迪亚斯大师了
Then you must know Master Sifo-Dyas.
伯巴，关上门
Boba, rood eht so-heeck.
哪位大师？
Master who?
西佛·迪亚斯
Sifo-Dyas.
不是这位绝地武士雇你们干这活的吗？
Is he not theJedi who hired you for this job?
从来没听说过
Never heard of him.
真的吗？
Really?
我是被一个叫泰瑞安斯的人招过来的
I was recruited by a man called Tyranus
在一颗博格登德卫星上
on one of the moons of Bogden.
奇怪
Curious.
你对你的军队还满意吗？
Do you like your army?
我期待见到他们真正的行动
I look forward to seeing them in action.
他们会干得很出色的，我向你保证
They'll do their job well. I'll guarantee that.
谢谢你抽出时间来见我，强格
Thank you for your time, Jango.
能会见绝地武士总是件愉快的事
Always a pleasure to meet a Jedi.
这是什么意思，爸？
What is it, Dad?
收拾好东西，我们要上路了
Pack your things. We're leaving.
当我遇到他们的时候，我们开始激烈的交涉，谢谢
And when I got to them, we went into aggressive negotiations.
“激烈的交涉”？为什么？
"Aggressive negotiations"? What's that?
嗯，为了一支光剑
Well, negotiations with a lightsaber.
要是欧比旺大师看到我这么做，他会气疯的
If Master Obi-Wan caught me doing this, he'd be very grumpy.
从我见到你的那一刻
From the moment I met you…
这么多年以来
all those years ago…
我无日无夜不在想你
not a day has gone by when I haven't thought of you.
而现在与你再次相聚
And now that I'm with you again…
令我苦恼倍增
I'm in agony.
与你越亲近情况越糟
The closer I get to you, the worse it gets.
一想到不能跟你在一起…
The thought of not being with you…
就令我无法呼吸
I can't breathe.
我被那个吻缠住了…
I'm haunted by the kiss…
是那个你永远不该给我的吻
that you should never have given me.
我的心灵悸动…
My heart is beating…
希望这个吻不会成为一道伤疤
hoping that that kiss will not become a scar.
你在我心灵深处…
You are in my very soul…
令我痛苦不已
tormenting me.
我还能怎么做？我愿做你吩咐的一切
What can I do? I will do anything that you ask.
要是你与我一样身受煎熬，求求你，告诉我
If you are suffering as much as I am, please, tell me.
我不能
I can't.
我们不能 这是…不可能的
We can't. It's… just not possible.
凡事都有可能，帕德梅，听我说
Anything is possible, Padmé. Listen to me.
不，你听我说
No, you listen.
我们生活在现实世界，回到现实吧
We live in a real world. Come back to it.
你在学习成为一个绝地武士，而我… 我是一个参议员
You're studying to become a Jedi. I'm a senator.
要是你再放任你的念头
If you follow your thoughts through to conclusion…
它会让我们误入歧途的
it'll take us to a place we cannot go…
不管我们对彼此的感觉如何
regardless of the way we feel about each other.
这么说你还是有感觉的
Then you do feel something.
我不会让你为我放弃大好前途
I will not let you give up your future for me.
你要求我理智
You are asking me to be rational.
这件事正是我清楚我做不到的
That is something I know I cannot do.
相信我，我也希望我能放下感情
Believe me, I wish that I could just wish away my feelings…
但我做不到
but I can't.
这事我不会让步的
I will not give in to this.
好吧，你知道，这…
Well, you know…
可以不必如此
it wouldn't have to be that way.
我们可以不让外人知道
We could keep it a secret.
我们会生活在谎言中
We'd be living a lie…
一个就算我们想保守也无法保守的秘密
one we couldn't keep even if we wanted to.
我不能这么做
I couldn't do that.
你能吗，安纳金？你能这么活着吗？
Could you, Anakin? Could you live like that?
不能，你说的没错
No. You're right.
这会毁了我们的
It would destroy us.
请转告你们参议会第一支军队已经准备就绪
Tell your council that the first battalions are ready.
再提醒他们，如果需要更多的军队
And remind them, if they need more troops…
就需要更多的时间培育他们
it will take more time to grow them.
记住了，谢谢你
I won't forget, and thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
R4！
R4!
用5号码加密接通克罗斯肯，当心这是他们的老巢！
Scramble code five to Coruscant, care of the old folks' home!
我已与卡米罗首相成功接触
I have successfully made contact with the prime minister of Kamino.
他们在用一个名叫强格·费特的赏金猎人
They are using a bounty hunter named Jango Fett
建造一支复制军队
to create a clone army.
我强烈感觉到这个赏金猎人
I have a strong feeling that this bounty hunter…
就是我们在找的刺客
is the assassin we are looking for.
你认为这些克隆人牵涉了…
Do you think these cloners are involved…
刺杀阿米达拉参议员的阴谋有关吗？
in the plot to assassinate Senator Amidala?
不，大师，看不出有什么动机
No, Master. There appears to be no motive.
任何事都不能想当然，欧比旺
Do not assume anything, Obi-Wan.
必须澄心静虑
Clear your mind must be…
如果你想找出这个阴谋幕后的罪魁祸首的话
if you are to discover the real villains behind this plot.
是，大师
Yes, Master.
他们说西佛·迪亚斯大师订购了这支复制军队…
They say Master Sifo-Dyas placed an order for a clone army…
差不多十年前以参议会的名义
at the request of the senate almost ten years ago.
我似乎记得他在这之前就死了
I was under the impression he was killed before that.
参议会曾经授意建造复制军队吗？
Did the council ever authorize the creation of a clone army?
没有 不管是谁订购的…
No. Whoever placed that order…
都没得到绝地参议会的批淮
did not have the authorization of theJedi Council.
把他带来 我们要盘问他
Bring him here. Question him we will.
是，大师，等我抓到他再向你报告
Yes, Master. I will report back when I have him.
我们真是瞎了眼了，要是连建造这样一支复制军队
Blind we are if creation of this clone army…
我们都看不见
we could not see.
我想是到了要告知议会
I think it is time we informed the senate…
我们运用原力的能力，已经削弱了的时候了
that our ability to use the Force has diminished.
只有黑暗之君西斯知道我们的弱点
Only the dark lord of the Sith knows of our weakness.
如果告知参议会
If informed the senate is…
就会增加我们的敌对者
multiply our adversaries will.
不
No.
妈，不
Mom, no.
别走
Don't go.
我不想打扰你
I don't want to disturb you.
你来了我安心多了
Your presence is soothing.
你昨晚又做恶梦了
You had another nightmare last night.
绝地武士不会做恶梦的
Jedi don't have nightmares.
我听到你的梦话了
I heard you.
我看到了我妈妈
I saw my mother.
她在受罪，帕德梅
She is suffering, Padmé.
我清楚地见到她，就像现在见到你一样
I saw her as clearly as I see you now.
她很痛苦
She is in pain.
我知道我这么做悖离了保护你的指令，参议员
I know I'm disobeying my mandate to protect you, Senator…
但我得走了
but I have to go.
我必须去帮助她
I have to help her.
我和你一起去
I'll go with you.
对不起，我别无选择
I'm sorry. I don't have a choice.
爸，小心！
Dad, look!
伯巴，上飞船！
Boba, get on board!
喔，这可不好
Oh, not good.
[胡图族语]
在那儿等我
Wait right there.
好的好的
Okey-okey.
[胡图族语]
Chut-chut, Watto.
让我帮帮你
Let me help you with that.
什么？你想干吗？
What? What do you want?
等一下！你是个绝地武士！
Wait! You're a Jedi!
不管是什么，我什么都没做
Whatever it is, I didn't do it.
我要找雪米·天行者（安纳金的母亲）
I'm looking for Shmi Skywalker.
安？
Ani?
小安？
Little Ani?
不不不
Nahhh.
你是安！真的是你！
You are Ani! It is you!
你长高多了，嗯？哇喔！
You sure sprouted, huh?
一个绝地武士！你知道吗！
A Jedi! Whattaya know!
也许你能帮我教训几个赖账不还的臭流氓
Maybe you could help with some deadbeats who owe me a lot of money.
我母亲
My mother.
哦，是的 雪米
Oh, yeah. Shmi.
她不属于我了… 不再是了，我把她卖了
She's not mine… a no more-a. I sold her.
- 你把她卖了？ - 好几年前的事了
- You sold her? - Years ago.
对不起，安，但你知道，生意就是生意，嗯？
Sorry, Ani, but you know, business is business.
是的，我把她卖给一个湿地农场主，嗯，叫拉斯的
I sold her to a moisture farmer named Lars.
至少我想他叫拉斯
At least I think it was Lars.
信不信由你，我听说他给了她自由还娶了她！
Believe it or not, I heard he freed her and married her!
竟然有这等事，嗯？是的
Can ya beat that, eh?
你知道他们现在在哪里吗？
Do you know where they are now?
离这儿可远了
Long way from here.
我想是在摩斯·埃斯里另一侧的什么地方
Someplace over on the other side of Mos Eisley, I think.
我想知道
I'd like to know.
当然，这不成问题！
Sure. Absolutely!
我们去看看我的记录，嗯？
Let's go look at my records, huh?
我想我们被跟踪了！
Dad! I think we're being tracked!
他一定是在我们船体上放了导航装置
He must have put a homing device on our hull.
坐稳，儿子，我们要进小行星区
Hang on, son. We'll move into the asteroid field…
再给他几个惊喜
and we'll have a couple of surprises for him.
震波弹！
Seismic charges!
准备好
Stand by.
他似乎不接受教训，这家伙
He doesn't seem to take a hint, this guy.
当心！
Watch out!
打他，爸！开火！
Get him, Dad! Fire!
该死！这就是我不喜欢飞行的原因！
Blast! This is why I hate flying!
我们打中他了！
We got him!
我们务必要解决掉他
We'll just have to finish him.
R4，准备把废弃的零件抛出去
R4, prepare to jettison the spare part canisters.
抛出去！
Fire them now!
好了，这下我们再也不会见到他了
We won't be seeing him again.
好，R4，我想我们在这里藏得够久了
Well, R4, I think we've waited long enough.
真奇怪有那么多贸易联邦的飞船停在这里，R4
There's an unusual concentration of Federation ships over there, R4.
待在飞船上，R2
Stay with the ship, R2.
你好 我能为您效劳吗？我是 C…
Hello. How might I be of service? I am C…
3PO？
3PO?
你是我的创造者！
The maker!
哦，主人！
Master Ani!
我就知道你一定会回来的 我早就知道！
I knew you would return. I knew it!
还有帕德梅小姐 哦，我的天
And Miss Padmé. Oh, my.
你好，3PO
Hello, 3PO.
上帝保佑我的电路板！能见到你们俩我太高兴了
Bless my circuits! I'm so pleased to see you both.
我是来见我母亲的
I've come to see my mother.
我想还是先进去再说吧
I think perhaps we'd better go indoors.
欧文主人，我荣幸的向您介绍两位尊贵的来客
Master Owen, might I present two most important visitors.
我是天行者安纳金
I'm Anakin Skywalker.
我是欧文·拉斯
Owen Lars.
- 这是我的女友，贝露 - 你好
- This is my girlfriend, Beru. - Hello.
我是帕德梅
I'm Padmé.
我想你是我的继母的孩子吧
I guess I'm your stepbrother.
我一直有一种感觉，总有一天你会出现的
I had a feeling you might show up someday.
我的母亲在这里吗？
Is my mother here?
不，她不在
No, she's not.
克力格·拉斯
Cliegg Lars.
她是我的妻子
Shmi is my wife.
我们进屋去，有许多事情要谈
We should go inside. We have a lot to talk about.
那是在破晓之前，他们从四面八方包围过来
It was just before dawn. They came out of nowhere.
那是塔斯肯人盗贼的一次狩猎
A hunting party ofTusken Raiders.
那天你母亲很早就出门了，她每天如此…
Your mother had gone out early, like she always did…
她是去摘蘑菇的
to pick mushrooms that grow on the vaporators.
从她的脚印可以看出，她大约是在走了一半的路程时…
From the tracks, she was about halfway home…
他们抓住她的
when they took her.
那些塔斯肯人像人类一样行走…
Those Tuskens walk like men…
但是他们都是邪恶，愚蠢的怪物
but they're vicious, mindless monsters.
我们派出了30个人去找他，只有四个人回来
Thirty of us went out after her. Four of us came back.
我本应和他们一起去的，但是自从我的腿断了以后…
I'd be out there with them, but after I lost my leg…
在我的腿治好之前，我不能够再驾驶了
I just couldn't ride anymore until I heal.
我不想放弃寻找…
I don't want to give up on her…
但是她已经被夺走有一个月了
but she's been gone a month.
她还活着的机会十分渺茫
There's little hope she's lasted this long.
你到哪儿去？
Where are you going?
找回我母亲
To find my mother.
你的母亲已经死了，孩子，接受这个事实吧
Your mother's dead, son. Accept it.
你得留在这里
You're gonna have to stay here.
他们都是好人，帕德梅，在这里你会很安全的
These are good people, Padmé. You'll be safe.
安纳金…
Anakin…
我很快就会回来的
I won't be long.
我们必须说服商业协会…
We must persuade the Commerce Guild…
和贸易联邦签署协定
and the Corporate Alliance to sign the treaty.
纳布星的参议员怎么办？
What about the senator from Naboo?
她死了没有？
Is she dead yet?
只要我没有看到她的人头，我就不会签署这份协定
I am not signing your treaty until I have her head on my desk.
我是个从不食言的人，总督
I am a man of my word, Viceroy.
只要你拥有这些我们为您制造的机器人战士…
With these new battle droids we've built for you…
您就拥有了银河系最强大的军队
you'll have the finest army in the galaxy.
就像我先前所说的那样…
As I explained to you earlier…
我确信还会再有超过一万个星系…
I am quite convinced that 10, 000 more systems…
加入我们，只要我能得到各位的支持
will rally to our cause with your support, gentlemen.
[外星语]你的计划是一种叛国
What you are proposing could be construed as treason.
我们科技工会的军队…
The Techno Union army…
愿意听从您的调遣，伯爵
is at your disposal, Count.
银行同业会愿意签署协定
The Banking Clan will sign your treaty.
好 非常好
Good. Very good.
我们来自贸易联邦的朋友也答应给予他们的支持…
Our friends from the Trade Federation have pledged their support…
等到他们的机器人战士与你们的会合之后…
and when their battle droids are combined with yours…
我们将拥有银河系最强大的军队
we shall have an army greater than any in the galaxy.
绝地武士将会被彻底击败
TheJedi will be overwhelmed.
共和国将不得不满足我们的任何要求
The Republic will agree to any demands we make.
妈妈？ 妈妈？
Mom? Mom?
安？
Ani?
是你吗？
Is it you?
我来了，妈妈，你没事了
I'm here, Mom. You're safe.
安？
Ani?
哦，你长得真帅
You look so handsome.
我的孩子
My son.
我的孩子长大了
My grown-up son.
我真为你感到自豪，安
I'm so proud of you, Ani.
我一直在想你
I missed you.
我就要离开你了
Now I am complete.
我爱你的…
I love y…
别离开我，妈妈，一切…
Stay with me, Mom. Everything…
我爱…
I love…
安纳金！
Anakin!
不！
No!
怎么了？
What is it?
痛苦，挣扎…
Pain, suffering…
我感到了死亡
death I feel.
发生了一件可怕的事
Something terrible has happened.
年轻的天行者正在痛苦之中…
Young Skywalker is in pain…
巨大的痛苦
terrible pain.
发射器工作正常，但是我们收不到任何回覆的讯号
The transmitter is working, but we're not receiving a return signal.
克罗斯肯太远了，R4，你能加大功率吗？
Coruscant's too far. R4, can you boost the power?
我们只有试试其他方法了
We'll have to try something else.
也许我们可以联系纳布星上的安纳金
Maybe we can contact Anakin on Naboo.
那里离我们近许多
It's much closer.
安纳金？安纳金，回话？
Anakin, do you copy?
我是欧比旺·肯诺比，安纳金？
This is Obi-Wan Kenobi. Anakin?
他不在纳布星上，R4
He's not on Naboo, R4.
让我试试看把频率范围扩大
I'm going to try and widen the range.
希望他不要出什么事
I do hope nothing's happened to him.
那是安纳金的讯号，好了…
That's Anakin's tracking signal, all right…
但是讯号来自塔图因星
but it's coming from Tatooine.
他在那里干什么？
What in the blazes is he doing there?
我叫他待在纳布星的
I told him to stay on Naboo.
我们没时间了
We haven't got much time.
安纳金？安纳金，收到没有？
Anakin, do you copy?
我是欧比旺·肯诺比
This is Obi-Wan Kenobi.
把我的讯息转送到…
Retransmit this message…
安纳金，收到没有？
Anakin, do you copy?
我的远程发报机被打坏了
My long-range transmitter has been knocked out.
把这份讯号转送到克罗斯肯
Retransmit this message to Coruscant.
我给你拿来些吃的东西
I brought you something.
你饿吗？
Are you hungry?
变速器坏了
The shifter broke.
在我修东西的时候总是感觉生活变得如此的简单
Life seems so much simpler when you're fixing things.
我很擅长修理，一直如此
I'm good at fixing things. Always was.
但是我却不能…
But I couldn't…
为什么她会死呢？
Why'd she have to die?
为什么我救不了她？
Why couldn't I save her?
我知道我本来应该能救她的！
I know I could have!
有时侯有些东西是修不好的
Sometimes there are things no one can fix.
- 你不是全能的，安 - 是吗，我应该是的！
- You're not all-powerful, Ani. - Well, I should be!
总有一天我会是的
Someday I will be.
我会成为有史以来最强大的绝地武士！
I will be the most powerfulJedi ever.
我向你发誓
I promise you.
我会学会怎样去拯救人们的生命
I will even learn to stop people from dying.
安纳金
Anakin.
这都是欧比旺的错！他嫉妒我！
It's all Obi-Wan's fault! He's jealous!
他总是束缚我！
He's holding me back!
发生了什么事，安？
What's wrong, Ani?
我杀了他们
I killed them.
我杀了他们所有的人
I killed them all.
他们都死了
They're dead.
每一个人
Every single one of them.
而且不光是男人…
And not just the men…
还有女人…
but the women…
和孩子
and the children too.
他们就像畜牲一样…
They're like animals…
我像屠宰畜牲一样的杀了他们！
and I slaughtered them like animals!
我恨他们！
I hate them!
愤怒是人类的本性
To be angry is to be human.
可我是个绝地武士
I'm a Jedi.
我知道我不是普通人
I know I'm better than this.
我知道无论你在哪里
I know wherever you are
那地方将变得更美好
it's become a better place.
你是这个世界中一个男人所能找到的最慈爱的伴侣
You were the most loving partner a man could ever have.
别了，我亲爱的妻子
Good-bye, my darling wife.
并感谢你
And thank you.
我不够强大来挽救你的生命，妈妈
I wasn't strong enough to save you, Mom.
我还不够强大
I wasn't strong enough.
但是我发誓我不会再失败了
But I promise I won't fail again.
我想你…
I miss you…
如此的想念你
so much.
R2？你来这里干吗？
R2? What are you doing here?
它好像带来了一个叫做欧比旺·肯诺比的人的消息
It seems that he is carrying a message from an Obi-Wan Kenobi.
安，这个名字是你认识的人的吗？
Master Ani, does that name mean anything to you?
安纳金，我的远程发射器坏了
Anakin, my long-range transmitter has been knocked out.
把我的讯息转送到克罗斯肯
Retransmit this message to Coruscant.
我一路追踪那个赏金猎人，强格·菲特…
I have tracked the bounty hunter, Jango Fett…
一直到了吉诺西斯星的机器人工厂
to the droid foundries on Geonosis.
贸易联邦打算向这里派送一支机器人大军…
The Trade Federation is to take delivery of a droid army here…
很清楚，刚雷总督…
and it is clear that Viceroy Gunray…
就是企图暗杀阿米达拉参议员的幕后指使者
is behind the assassination attempts on Senator Amidala.
商业协会和贸易联邦…
The Commerce Guilds and the Corporate Alliance…
都同意将他们的军队
have both pledged their armies
交由杜库伯爵指挥，并正在组成…
to Count Dooku and are forming…
等一下，等一下
Wait.
我感到在吉诺西斯星上发生的事比我们已知的还要多
More happening on Geonosis, I feel, than has been revealed.
我同意
I agree.
安纳金，我们会对付杜库伯爵
We will deal with Count Dooku.
你最重要的任务就是待在原地
The most important thing for you is to stay where you are.
不惜一切代价保护参议员
Protect the senator at all costs.
这是你的首要任务
That is your first priority.
明白，大师
Understood, Master.
他们不可能及时赶到那里去营救他
They'll never get there in time to save him.
他们要穿越半个银河系之远 看
They have to come halfway across the galaxy. Look.
吉诺西斯星离这里只有不到一个秒差的距离
（注：1秒差＝3.26光年＝30000000000000公里）
Geonosis is less than a parsec away.
如果他还活着的话
If he's still alive.
你打算就坐在这里让他等死吗？
Are you just gonna sit here and let him die?
- 他是你的朋友，你的师父 - 他就像是我的父亲！
- He's your friend, your mentor. - He's like my father!
但是你也听到了温杜大师的话，他命令我必须待在这里
But you heard Master Windu. He gave me strict orders to stay here.
他命令你必须保护我…
He gave you strict orders to protect me…
而我要去救欧比旺
and I'm going to help Obi-Wan.
如果你打算保护我，那么你就必须和我一起去
If you plan to protect me, you'll just have to come along.
我一点都不害怕，R2，只不过我以前从来没乘过飞船
I'm not worried, R2. It's just I've never flown before.
商业协会正在备战
The Commerce Guilds are preparing for war.
这点毫无疑问
There can be no doubt of that.
杜库伯爵一定已经和他们签定了协议
Count Dooku must have made a treaty with them.
[外星语]辩论已经结束
The debate is over.
现在我们需要那支克隆人大军
Now we need that clone army.
不幸的是辩论还未结束
Unfortunately, the debate is not over.
参议员是不会批准使用克隆人部队的…
The senate will never approve the use of clones…
在分裂分子正式发动进攻前
before the separatists attack.
现在是紧急情况
This is a crisis.
必须要让参议院通过投票赋予首相大人非常时期领导权
The senate must vote the chancellor emergency powers.
这样他才能有权批准制造克隆人部队
He can then approve the creation of an army.
但是哪位参议员会有如此的勇气…
But what senator would have the courage…
来提议这样一份激进的法案呢？
to propose such a radical amendment?
如果… 阿米达拉参议员在这里就好了
If only Senator Amidala were here.
叛徒
Traitor.
哦，你弄错了，我的朋友，这是个误会，很大的误会
Oh, no, my friend. This is a mistake, a terrible mistake.
他们做的太过分了，真是疯狂的行为
They have gone too far. This is madness.
我以为你是这里的领导人，杜库
I thought you were the leader here, Dooku.
我向你保证我与此事毫无瓜葛
This had nothing to do with me, I assure you.
我会立即请求他们将你释放的
I will petition immediately to have you set free.
啊，我希望能快一点 我还有工作要做
Well, I hope it doesn't take too long. I have work to do.
我是否能够请问，像您这样一位绝地武士…
May I ask why a Jedi knight…
为什么会来到这个偏僻的星球，吉诺西斯
is all the way out here on Geonosis?
我一路的追踪一个叫强格·费特的赏金猎人来到了这里
I've been tracking a bounty hunter named Jango Fett.
你认识他吗？
Do you know him?
我在这里从未看到过任何赏金猎人
There are no bounty hunters here that I am aware of.
吉诺西斯人不信任赏金猎人
The Geonosians don't trust them.
这很正常，但是他就在这里，这点我很肯定
Who can blame them? But he is here, I can assure you.
真是遗憾，我们以前从未能够谋面，欧比旺
It's a great pity our paths have never crossed before, Obi-Wan.
魁刚金一直给与你很高的赞扬
Qui-Gon always spoke very highly of you.
真希望他还在人世
I wish he were still alive.
那样的话他现在就能助我一臂之力了
I could use his help right now.
魁刚金绝无可能与你合作
Qui-Gon Jinn would never join you.
别轻易的下结论，我年轻的绝地武士
Don't be so sure, my young Jedi.
难道你忘了他曾经是我的徒弟…
You forget that he was once my apprentice…
就像你曾经是他的徒弟一样
just as you were once his.
对于参议院内的腐败他一清二楚…
He knew all about the corruption in the senate…
但他不会去服从参议院的命令
but he wouldn't have gone along with it
如果他像我一样了解事实真相
if he had learned the truth as I have.
- 事实真相？ - 对，事实真相
- The truth? - The truth.
如果我告诉你整个共和国现在已受制于…
What if I told you that the Republic was now under the control…
西斯黑暗大君的掌控之下？
of the dark lord of the Sith?
不，那绝不可能，绝地武士会肯定会察觉到的
No, that's not possible. The Jedi would be aware of it.
黑暗原力的浓雾已经蒙蔽了他们的洞察力，我的朋友
The dark side of the Force has clouded their vision, my friend.
成百的参议员已经…
Hundreds of senators are now under the influence…
在一个名为达斯·西迪斯的黑暗大帝的控制之下
of a Sith lord called Darth Sidious.
我不相信
I don't believe you.
贸易联邦的总督…
The viceroy of the Trade Federation…
曾经与达斯·西迪斯结盟…
was once in league with this Darth Sidious…
但是十年前他被黑暗大帝出卖了
but he was betrayed ten years ago by the dark lord.
他来找我求助，他告诉了一切
He came to me for help. He told me everything.
你一定要与我合作，欧比旺…
You must join me, Obi-Wan…
让我们一起来消灭西斯！
and together we will destroy the Sith!
我永远不会与你合作，杜库
I will never join you, Dooku.
看来要释放你会变得很困难了
It may be difficult to secure your release.
十分肯定的是这些分裂分子已经签定了一份公约…
It's-a clear desa separatists made a pact…
其中包括贸易联邦
wesa desa Federation du Trade.
诸位参议员们，“行动起来”
Senators, "dellow felagates":
对此共和国面临的迫在眉睫的危机…
In response to this direct threat to the Republic…
我提议参议院…
mesa propose that the senate…
立即将非常时期领导权赋予…
give immediately emergency powers…
首相大人
to the supreme chancellor.
帕裴丁！帕裴丁！
Palpatine! Palpatine!
安静！ 请大家恢复秩序！
Order! We shall have order!
我十分为难的…
It is with great reluctance…
接受这项请求
that I have agreed to this calling.
我热爱民主，我热爱共和国
I love democracy. I love the Republic.
诸位赋予我的权力…
The power you give me…
我会在此次危机缓和之后交还
I will lay down when this crisis has abated.
作为对于我所拥有的权力的首次使用…
And as my first act with this new authority…
我将批准为共和国建立一支强大的军队…
I will create a grand army of the Republic…
以应付分裂分子愈来愈近的威胁
to counter the increasing threats of the separatists.
如此一来，一切已经决定了
It is done, then.
我会带领所有剩下的绝地武士
I will take what Jedi we have left
赶往吉诺西斯去营救欧比旺大师
and go to Geonosis and help Obi-Wan.
我会去查访一下卡米罗星上的克隆人，嗯…
Visit I will the cloners on Kamino…
去亲眼看一下他们为共和国建立的这支军队
and see this army they have created for the Republic.
看见前方的烟柱了吗？
See those columns of steam straight ahead?
它们是通风管排出的废气
They're exhaust vents of some type.
让我来
That'll do.
听着，不管发生什么事情，你都要服从我的指挥
Look, whatever happens out there, follow my lead.
我不想在这里和他们开战
I'm not interested in getting into a war here.
作为参议院的成员…
As a member of the senate…
也许我能通过外交方式解决争端
maybe I can find a diplomatic solution to this mess.
别担心
Don't worry.
我已经放弃再和你争论了
I've given up trying to argue with you.
我可爱的小朋友，如果他们需要我们的帮助…
My obtuse little friend, if they had needed our help…
他们会告诉我们的，不是吗？
they would have asked for it.
看来对于人类的行为方式，你还有很多要学的
You obviously have a great deal to learn about human behavior.
对于一个机器人来说，你考虑得太多了
For a mechanic, you seem to do an excessive amount of thinking.
我的程序设计就是让我来理解人类的！
I am programmed to understand humans!
「你问我这是什么意思？」 哦！
"What does that mean?"
意思就是这里我说了算！
That means I am in charge here!
你要上哪儿去？
Where are you going now?
你不知道那里有多危险 难道你一点都没有感到吗？
You don't know what's out there. Have you no sense at all?
白痴！
Idiot!
请等一下
Please wait.
你知道你要去哪儿吗？
Do you know where you're going?
等一下
Wait.
帕德梅！
哦，我的天啊！
Oh, my goodness!
把我关掉吧！
Shut me down!
机器制造机器
Machines making machines.
哈！ 真是奇怪，哦！
How perverse!
安静，R2！
Calm down, R2!
我差点摔下去
I almost fell.
会让你看的…
You'll get your chance…
哦！ 我被扔掉了
I'm scrap.
这像是一场恶梦！
It's a nightmare!
哦，我要回家！啊！
I want to go home!
哦，我到底干了什么落到这个下场？
What did I do to deserve this?
不知道可怜的小R2现在怎么样
I wonder what happened to poor little R2.
他总是给自己惹麻烦
He's always getting himself into trouble.
哦，不！
Oh, no!
喔
Uh-oh.
哦，到底怎么回事
I'm so confused.
噢，又来了！
Not again!
这下欧比旺会杀了我的
Obi-Wan's gonna kill me.
不许动，绝地武士！
Don't move, Jedi!
把他带走
Take him away.
不用怕
Don't be afraid.
我不害怕去死
I'm not afraid to die.
每天我都像死一样的受着折磨
I've been dying a little bit each day
自从你重回到我的生活中以来
since you came back into my life.
我不懂你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
我爱你
I love you.
你爱我？
You love me?
我原以为我们已经决定不再去爱对方了…
I thought we had decided not to fall in love…
在以后的人生中，我们都必须不断的欺骗自己…
that we would be forced to live a lie…
那样我们的生命实际已经结束
and that it would destroy our lives.
我想现在无论如何我们的生命都将结束了
I think our lives are about to be destroyed anyway.
我是真的…
I truly…
深深的－爱着你…
deeply love you…
在我们死之前，我要让你知道
and before we die, I want you to know.
我现在开始怀疑你是否收到了我的讯息
I was beginning to wonder if you'd got my message.
我完全按你所说的把讯息转送了，师父
I retransmitted it just as you had requested, Master.
然后我们决定来救你
Then we decided to come and rescue you.
干的不错啊
Good job.
安静 安静
Settle down. Settle down.
处决开始
Let the executions begin.
我觉得不太妙…
I've got a bad feeling about this.
- 放松，集中注意力 - 帕德梅怎么办？
- Just relax. Concentrate. - What about Padmé?
她好像已经爬到什么东西的顶上了
She seems to be on top of things.
不能让她这么做！
She can't do that!
枪决她… 或类似方式！
Shoot her… or something!
快跳！
Jump!
怎么会变成这样！
This isn't how it's supposed to be!
强格！杀了她！
Jango! Finish her off!
耐心，总督，请保持耐心，我会让她死的
Patience, Viceroy, patience. She will die.
温杜大师
Master Windu.
真高兴你也来了
How pleasant of you to join us.
派对结束了
This party's over.
你很勇敢…
Brave…
但是有点愚蠢，我的老朋友
but foolish, my old Jedi friend.
你们的人数少的可怜
You're impossibly outnumbered.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
让我们走着瞧吧
We'll see.
我的腿动不了了，我需要维修
My legs aren't moving. I must need maintenance.
什么声音那么吵？打仗了！
What's all this noise? A battle!
哦，你们完全搞错了！
There's been some terrible mistake!
我是个文雅的礼仪机器人，我不是战斗机器人！
I'm programmed for etiquette, not destruction!
去死吧，绝地狗！
Die, Jedi dogs!
噢！我刚才说什么了？
Oh! What did I say?
哦，亲爱的，我真是太抱歉了
Oh, dear. I'm terribly sorry about all this.
请原谅，我被你压住了，让我起来
Excuse me. I'm trapped. I can't get up.
这就是你说的外交解决吗？
You call this a diplomatic solution?
不，我称之为激烈谈判
No, I call it aggressive negotiations.
- 啊哦 - 收到，收到
- Uh-oh. - Roger, roger.
R2，你在这里干什么？
R2, what are you doing here?
你想做什么？
What are you doing?
快停下来！你拉住我的什么东西
Stop that! You're going to strain something.
我的头！
My neck!
现在你要把我带到哪里去？我的头被你拽的好难受！
Now where are you taking me? This is such a drag!
喔，我已经到了自己的身体边上了
I'm quite beside myself.
R2，请小心一点！你要烧焦我的电路板了！
R2, please be careful! You're singeing my circuits!
好，但是我的头的位置有没有对正？
Yes, but is my head on straight?
温杜大师…
Master Windu…
你们的战斗很精彩…
you have fought gallantly…
值得载入绝地武士的史册之中
worthy of recognition in the archives of theJedi order.
现在…
Now…
它已经结束了
it is finished.
投降吧…
Surrender…
我会放你们一条生路
and your lives will be spared.
我们不会成为你们用来交换的人质，杜库！
We will not be hostages to be bartered, Dooku!
那样的话…
Then…
我很遗憾，老朋友
I'm sorry, old friend.
看！
Look!
围绕着悻存者的四周射击
Around the survivors a perimeter create.
哦，我做了一个十分怪异的梦
I've had the most peculiar dream!
如果让杜库逃跑了…
If Dooku escapes…
他将会去召集更多反叛的星系
rally more systems to his cause he will.
抓紧了！
Hold on!
朝能源炉上射击！
Aim right above the fuel cells!
干得好，我年轻的徒弟
Good call, my young Padawan.
绝地武士聚集了一支庞大的军队
TheJedi have amassed a huge army.
但是这应该是不可能的
That doesn't seem possible.
绝地武士怎么可能那么快带来一支如此大的军队？
How could theJedi come up with an army so quickly?
我们必须把所有的机器人士兵投入战斗
We must send all available droids into battle.
他们的人数太多了
There are too many.
我们的对外通讯被切断了
Our communications have been jammed.
驾驶，在那个集合点降落！
Pilot, land in that assembly area!
是，长官
Yes, sir.
长官…
Sir…
我召集了五支特别突击队听候您的调遣
I have five special commando units awaiting your orders, sir.
把我带到前方的指挥部
To the forward command center take me.
攻击那些联邦的星舰！快！
Attack those Federation starships, quickly!
尤达大师，各路前锋部队都在向前突进
Master Yoda, all forward positions are advancing.
很好
Very good.
情况看上去一点都不好！
This is not looking good at all!
我们必须乘上星舰返回外太空
We must get the starships back into space.
我们必须下达命令撤退
We have to order a retreat.
我的主人绝不会允许共和国…
My master will never allow the Republic…
因为这种背信的行为而取得胜利
to get away with this treachery.
我已经让我的战士躲藏到了地下墓穴
I'm sending my warriors to hide in the catacombs.
绝不能让绝地武士发现我们开发的终极武器
TheJedi must not find our designs for the ultimate weapon.
如果他们发觉了我们正打算建造的东西，我们就完蛋了
If they find out what we are planning to build, we're doomed.
我会将设计图带到克罗斯肯
I will take the designs with me to Coruscant.
由我的主人保管它将会很安全
They will be much safer there with my master.
集中所有火力攻击最近的那艘星舰
Concentrate all your fire on the nearest starship.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
所有火力集中到5-1-5区域
Move all quadrants to sector 515.
看那里！
Look over there!
是杜库！把他打下来！
It's Dooku! Shoot him down!
我们的导弹用完了，长官
We're out of rockets, sir.
- 跟着他！ - 我们需要支援！
- Follow him! - We're gonna need some help!
没时间了！我和安纳金能够应付！
There isn't time! Anakin and I can handle this!
帕德梅！
- 把飞船停下来！ - 安纳金！
- Put the ship down! - Anakin!
不要让你的个人感情左右你！
Don't let your personal feelings get in the way!
跟上那摩托艇！
Follow that speeder!
- 把船停下！ - 我一个人不能应付杜库！
- Lower the ship! - I can't take Dooku alone!
我需要你！
I need you!
如果我们能够抓住他，我们就能马上结束战争！
If we catch him, we can end this war right now!
- 我们需要完成任务！ - 我不在乎任务！ 把船停下！
- We have a job to do! - I don't care! Put the ship down!
你这样做会被驱逐出绝地武士团！
You will be expelled from theJedi order!
- 我不能丢下她！ - 恢复理智吧！
- I can't leave her! - Come to your senses!
想一下如果帕德梅处在你的位置之下她会怎么做？
What do you think Padmé would do were she in your position?
她会尽她的职责
She would do her duty.
机器人军队已经全线撤退
The droid army is in full retreat.
干的好，指挥官，给我调一艘飞船来
Well done, Commander. Bring me a ship.
你会为你今天所杀的绝地武士付出代价，杜库
You're gonna pay for all the Jedi that you killed today, Dooku.
我们一起来对付他
We'll take him together.
- 我现在就来解决他！ - 不，安纳金！不！
- I'm taking him now! - No, Anakin! No!
就像你所见到的那样，我的绝地武士力量远胜于你们
As you see, my Jedi powers are far beyond yours.
趁现在… 快回去吧
Now… back down.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
肯诺比大师，你真是让我失望了
Master Kenobi, you disappoint me.
尤达大师是如此的欣赏你
Yoda holds you in such high esteem.
你肯定应该能做的更好的
Surely you can do better.
你没事吗？
Are you all right?
我们最好还是赶快回前方指挥部
We'd better get back to the forward command center.
不
No.
召集所有你所能召集的士兵，我们必须赶到那里的机库
Gather what troops you can. We've got to get to that hangar.
找一艘运输机，快！
Get a transport. Hurry!
马上就去
Right away.
勇气可嘉，孩子
Brave of you, boy.
但是我以为你刚才应该已经吸取教训了
But I would have thought you had learned your lesson.
- 我是个不吸取教训的人 - 安纳金！
- I am a slow learner. - Anakin!
尤达大师
Master Yoda.
杜库伯爵
Count Dooku.
这将是你最后一次的阻碍我的行动
You have interfered with our affairs for the last time.
你变得更强大了，杜库
Powerful you have become, Dooku.
我在你身上感到了黑暗的力量
The dark side I sense in you.
我的力量已经超越了任何绝地武士
I've become more powerful than anyJedi.
甚至包括你
Even you.
你还有许多要学的
Much to learn you still have.
很明显我们之间战斗的胜负不是…
It is obvious that this contest cannot be decided…
由对原力知识的多少来决定的…
by our knowledge of the Force…
而是由我们剑术的高下来决定
but by our skills with a lightsaber.
你的剑术不赖，我的老徒弟
Fought well you have, my old Padawan.
这才刚开始
This is just the beginning.
安纳金！
Anakin!
原力属于我们，西迪斯大师
The Force is with us, Master Sidious.
欢迎回来，泰伦斯阁下
Welcome home, Lord Tyranus.
你做的很好
You have done well.
有好消息带给您，阁下
I have good news for you, my lord.
- 战争已经开始了 - 很好
- The war has begun. - Excellent.
一切都已照计划进行
Everything is going as planned.
你相信杜库伯爵所说的
Do you believe what Count Dooku said
关于西迪斯控制了参议院的事情吗？
about Sidious controlling the senate?
感觉好像不太可能
It doesn't feel right.
杜库已经加入了黑暗的一方
Joined the dark side Dooku has.
谎言，欺骗…
Lies, deceit…
并制造猜疑已经成为了他所使用的伎俩
creating mistrust are his ways now.
尽管如此…
Nevertheless…
我觉得还是应该严密的监视参议院的动向
I feel we should keep a closer eye on the senate.
我同意
I agree.
你的徒弟在哪里？
Where is your apprentice?
他到纳布星去了，护送阿米达拉参议院回国
On his way to Naboo, escorting Senator Amidala home.
我不得不承认如果没有克隆人军队
I have to admit that without the clones,
我们不可能取得胜利
it would not have been a victory.
胜利？
Victory?
你是说胜利吗？
Victory, you say?
欧比旺大师，这不是胜利
Master Obi-Wan, not victory.
黑暗势力的阴影已经笼罩了过来
The shroud of the dark side has fallen.
克隆人战争已经开始
Begun the Clone War has.